A story of when good food... goes bad!
Foodfight! is a adventure, comedy, action film directed by Lawrence Kasanoff.
The evil Brand X joins a supermarket that becomes a city after closing time.
Dex Dogtective (voice), played by Charlie Sheen.
Sunshine Goodness (voice), played by Hilary Duff.
Lady X (voice), played by Eva Longoria.
Daredevil Dan (voice), played by Wayne Brady.
Mr. Clipboard (voice), played by Christopher Lloyd.
Polar Penguin (voice), played by Chris Kattan.
is a 2012 American animated adventure comedy film co-produced and directed by Lawrence Kasanoff (in his feature directorial debut), who wrote
the screenplay with Brent Friedman, Rebecca Swanson and Sean Catherine Derek from a story Kasanoff conceived with Joshua Wexler.
The film features the voices of Charlie Sheen, Wayne Brady, Hilary
Duff, Eva Longoria, Larry Miller, and Christopher Lloyd.
takes place in the "Marketropolis" supermarket, which, after closing time, transforms into
a city inhabited by "Ikes", personifications of well-known food mascots.
The story follows a cereal brand mascot, Dex Dogtective, who, along with his best friend Daredevil Dan, join forces with their
fellow "Ikes" to fight against the forces of the evil Brand X, who threaten to take over the entire supermarket.
After raising tens of millions of dollars in funding, Foodfight!
had a troubled and much-delayed production.
The film was originally scheduled for a Christmas 2003 theatrical release; however, this failed to
materialize, and later planned release dates in 2005 and 2007 were also missed.
By September 2011, after the producers defaulted on a loan, creditors auctioned off the
film's assets and all associated rights to Fireman's Fund Insurance Company.
In 2012, the film had a modest release, being
direct-to-video in most territories.
Its critical reception was overwhelmingly negative, with most criticism directed
towards the animation, humor, story and excessive product placement.
It has often been discussed as one of the worst films of all time.
The film explores themes of supermarket, fight,
product placement, food, food fight.
The tone is lighthearted.